touchnote.com 2019-06-29

# Privacy Policy - TouchNote

Our privacy policy is a way for us to explain how we’re looking after you and your details. Please don’t be put off by how formal it sounds (we did it for the lawyers).

If you’ve got questions about anything we’ve written here, please get in touch at [help@touchnote.com](mailto:help@touchnote.com) so we can shed some light on it.

### **INTRODUCTION**

At Touchnote, we believe that as our valued customer you have a fundamental right to privacy and to control your personal information. We are grateful that you have chosen to be our customer and we take the responsibility of not only printing and posting your cards, but also of being guardians of the personal information that you give us, extremely seriously.

This privacy policy together with our terms of use ([https://www.touchnote.com/terms/](https://www.touchnote.com/terms/)) sets out how Touchnote Limited, (“we”, “our”) will use any personal data we collect from you, or you provide to us, during your use of our products and services (whether existing now or in the future) (the “Services”) at [www.touchnote.com](https://www.touchnote.com/) or through our Touchnote mobile app (together our “Platform”). Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting the Platform you accept and consent to the practices described in this policy.

For the purpose of the General Data Protection Regulations (the “Regulations”), the data controller is Touchnote Limited of Ground & Basement Floors, 17-18 Clere Street, Old Street, London EC2A 4LJ. We may from time to time use data processors, who are not employees, agents or otherwise connected with us, with whom we have an agreement to process your data.

### **INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM YOU**

We will collect and process the following data about you:

Information you give us. This is information about you that you give us by filling in forms on our Platform or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. It includes information you provide when you register to use our Platform, or use our Services, place an order on our Platform, enter a competition, promotion or survey on the Platform and when you report a problem with our Platform. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, financial and credit card information. In order to take advantage of some of our Services, you may need to supply us with the personal details of a third party (for example, their name and address if you wish to send them some of our products). We will not use this information for anything other than providing the Service for which the information was supplied.

Information we collect about you. With regard to each of your visits to our Platform we will automatically collect the following information:

technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information (when you sign in as a customer), browser type and version, and the type of device used to access the Platform; information about your visit, including the clickstream to, through and from our Platform (including date and time), products you viewed or searched for, page response times, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and any phone number used to call our customer service number. This can be stored in both video and word form and may allow us to access session videos designed to better illustrate how users interact with the platform. 

We are not aware of the identity of the User from which we have collected Non- Personal Information. Non-Personal Information is any unconcealed information which is available to us while Users are using the Service. Non-personal Information which is being gathered consists of technical information and behavioral information and which may include, the User’s Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your uniform resource locators (URL), operating system, type of browser, browser plug-in types and versions, screen resolution, Flash version, time zone setting, the User’s ‘click-stream’ on the website, the period of time the User visited the website, methods used to browse away from a page, and any phone number used to call our customer service number.

Information we receive from other sources. We work with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers) and may receive some information that is not personal information because it does not identify you or anyone else. For example, we may collect anonymous aggregated information about how users use our services.

We do not knowingly solicit or collect any information about users who may be under the age of 16, and will delete any information provided by such individuals as soon as possible. Please do not provide us with any personal information if you are under the age of 16.  While we do allow users under the age of 16 to use the Platform, any users under the age of 18 should discuss the use of the Platform with their parents before they submit or upload any content to the Platform.

### **USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION**

We use information held about you in the following ways:

Information you give to us. We will use this information:

to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and Services that you request from us;

to provide you with information about other products and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about;

to provide you with information about products or services we feel may interest you. If you are an existing customer, we may contact you by e-mail, SMS or direct mail with information about products and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale to you. If you are a new customer, we will contact you by the above means if you have consented to this when you signed up to the TouchNote platform. If you do not want us to use your data in this way please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data (for example, the order form or registration form) or contacting us at help@touchnote.com.

to carry out market research and the tracking of sales;

to notify you about changes to our Services;

to ensure that content from our Platform is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.

Information we collect about you. We will use this information:

to administer our Platform and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;

to improve our Platform to ensure that content is presented in the most effective and safe manner for you and for your computer;

to allow you to participate in interactive features of our Services, when you choose to do so;

to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you;

to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Platform about goods or services that may interest you or them.

### **DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION**

You agree that we have the right to share your personal information in the following ways:

With any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

With selected third parties including:

business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you;

Analytics, including the use of session videos and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our Platform.

With third parties:

In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we will disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

If Touchnote Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.

where a third party claims that any content posted or uploaded by you to our Platform constitutes a violation of their intellectual property rights, or of their right to privacy.

If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use ([https://www.touchnote.com/terms/](https://www.touchnote.com/terms/)) and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Touchnote Limited, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

### **WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

The data that we collect from you will be transferred to, and stored at, a destination within the European Economic Area (“EEA”) but may include storage in the cloud outside of the EEA. It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. This includes staff engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing, including such transfer storing or processing in any cloud service. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. You further specfically consent to our sending your information outside the EEA to countries including but not limited to the Phillipines, Jamaica and Kenya for the servicing of your Customer Support Request,

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers in the Republic of Ireland. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

### **RETENTION OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will retain your personal data for so long as is necessary for the purposes stated in this Privacy Policy and to address any claims or issues that may arise concerning your use of our Services.

After that, we may continue to hold data that relates to you and your use of our Platform for research and statistical analysis, as permitted under the relevant sections of the Regulations. However, during the time you may contact us to request that we delete personal data we hold about you.

### **YOUR RIGHTS**

You have the right to ask us to erase your personal data or not to process your personal data. We will inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for marketing purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by unchecking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at help@touchnote.com.

If at any point you believe the information we process on you is incorrect you may ask to see this information and have it corrected or deleted. You also have the right to ask that we restrict the processing of your personal data and to object to our processing of your personal data. You also have the right to obtain from us, and reuse, the personal data we maintain from you, for your own purposes.

If you wish to lodge a complaint over the way in which we have handled your personal data, you can contact us at gdpr@touchnote.com. If you are dissatisfied with our response you may contact the UK Information Commissioner’s Office or the equivalent supervisory bodies in non-UK jurisdictions.

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### **CARD TRANSACTIONS**

Your full card details are not recorded or stored in our database. We only collect and store the final four numbers of your credit or debit card together with the expiry date and cardholder name in order for you to be able to select that card when making a future purchase. The details are encrypted and transferred securely to one or more third party payment service providers.

### **COOKIES AND LOCAL STORAGE**

When you access or use the Service, we may use industry-wide technologies such as “cookies” or similar technologies, which stores certain information on your computer (“Local Storage”) and which will allow us to enable automatic activation of certain features, and make your Service experience much more convenient and effortless. The cookies used by the Service are created per session and does not include any information about you, other than your session key (usually removed as your session ends but sometimes can be kept in your device for no more than 6 months) and the ability to login again quickly. Most browsers will allow you to erase cookies from your computer’s hard drive, block acceptance of cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. However, if you block or erase cookies your online experience with the Service may be limited.

We use Cookies and other technologies on the basis that they are necessary for the performance of a contract with you, or because using them is in our legitimate interests (where we have considered that these are not overridden by your rights).

TouchNote uses secured Cookies. That means a cookie with a secured flag which can only be transmitted over an encrypted connection. This makes the cookie less likely to be exposed to cookie theft via eavesdropping.

We use the following types of Cookies:

**Strictly necessary cookies.** These are cookies that are required for the operation of our Site and under our terms with you. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our Service.

**Analytical/performance cookies.** They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our Site when they are using it. This helps us for our legitimate interests of improving the way our Service works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.

**Functionality cookies.** These are used to recognise you when you return to our Site. This enables us, subject to your choices and preferences, to personalise our content, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).

**Disabling cookies**

The effect of disabling cookies depends on which cookies you disable but, in general, the Service may not operate properly if cookies are switched off. If you only disable third party cookies, you will not be prevented from making purchases on our sites. If you disable all cookies, you will be unable to use our Services.

If you want to disable cookies on our site, you need to change your browser settings to reject cookies. How you can do this will depend on the browser you use. Further details on how to disable cookies can be found here:

Internet Explorer – [http://windows.microsoft.com/en-GB/internet-explorer/delete-manage-cookies](http://windows.microsoft.com/en-GB/internet-explorer/delete-manage-cookies)

Google Chrome – https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en

Firefox – https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences

Safari – http://help.apple.com/safari/mac/8.0/#/sfri11471

Except for essential cookies, all cookies used on our site will expire at the end of the session

### **ACCESS TO INFORMATION**

The Regulations gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Regulations.

### **CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

TouchNote reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time and its sole discretion, so please re-visit this page frequently. We will provide notice of substantial changes of this Privacy Policy on the Site or via Email. Such substantial changes will take effect seven (7) days after such notice was provided on any of the above mentioned methods. Otherwise, all other changes to this Privacy Policy are effective as of the stated “Last Revised” date, and your continued use of the App after the Last Revised date will constitute acceptance of, and agreement to be bound by, those changes.

### **CONTACT**

E.U. citizens have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority (Data Protection Authority in your jurisdiction) in case of a breach of any E.U. data protection and privacy regulations. If the supervisory authority fails to deal with a complaint or inform you within the time frame set under applicable law, you have the right to an effective judicial remedy.

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to: The Data Protection Officer, TouchNote Ltd, Ground & Basement Floors, 17-18 Clere Street, London, EC2A 4LJ or via email to gdpr@touchnote.com
